# **James Nduka**

Email: james.s.nduka@synwin.co.uk LinkedIn: URL GitHub: URL

### **PROFILE**

A versatile Solutions Architect and Engineer with several years' experience in Development Architecture, DevOps and Configuration Management of on-premise and Cloud based environments (AWS & Azure).

I have been involved in engagements varying from the financial and banking industries to utility companies and retail, where I have been responsible for strategizing the DevOps architecture for traditional and non-traditional enterprise applications whilst effectively applying practices, processes and tools in place for automation and Continuous Delivery.

Also, a certified AWS Solutions Architect and SysOps Administrator that has designed and implemented fault-tolerant/highly available infrastructure and services in the cloud.

### KEY ACHEVEMENTS

- Designed and developed several automated deployment pipelines which has accelerated delivery by over 35% and increased the number of application code deployments occurring each day
- Key in implementing innovative public and private cloud solutions for clients in the financial, utilities, pharmaceutical and retail sector.
- Positioned as a DevOps SME within Accenture's shared service, providing process enhancements and tools expertise in the key areas of the software development lifecycle
- Rationalizing Infrastructure-as-code, using AWS CloudFormation & Hashicorp's Terraform to stand
  up staging, QA and pre-prod environments before using Chef to deploy and configure the
  application releases on top of the instances. As a result, this saved the business of over 40% in
  unnecessary spending on on-premise server capacity

### EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

## AstraZeneca, Cambridge

Mar 2019 – Oct 2019

### Senior SysOps Engineer (contract)

- Apart of the SysOps team in Science & Enabling Units. Responsible for servicing the AWS infrastructure needs of some of AstraZeneca's advanced architectures.
- Working with highly scalable advanced AWS resources such as Amazon ECS, Batch, Lambda, Step Functions and Athena
- Assisting the functional genomics project which was in collaboration between AstraZeneca & Cancer Research UK to build the AWS architecture fit for advanced data screening and analysis.
- Engineered the CI/CD pipeline for Docker images used for the genomics project. The output Docker images were then pushed to both Amazon ECR and DockerHub
- Adhering to strict AWS security practices and cloud operational standards such as CIS compliance
- Using tools such as Chef for Linux & Windows config management, Jenkins for CI/CD, Packer for image creation and CloudFormation for infrastructure definition.
- Worked in an Agile development manner supporting rapid change to Dev, SIT, Pre-Prod and Prod environments

### **Senior Cloud Technical Architect** (contract)

- Responsible for the architecture of the Azure "Development" and "Test" environments across two subscriptions, which was a mixture of 100 Windows 2016 and Ubuntu server machines
- Working closely with the infrastructure strategy and architecture team at clients such as Allen & Overy LLP
- Planning and implementing the rollout of Chef Server and Chef Automate v2 for the management of the config and compliance/security for 100 Windows and Linux
- Conversion of existing, laborious PowerShell and Bash scripts into a collection of sophisticated Chef cookbooks to manage the automation of configuration for the nodes
- Creation and modification of InSpec profiles to ensure all deployed nodes were kept in a compliant state
- Designed and implemented the CI/CD pipeline for all infrastructure-as-code artifacts

### Ladbrokes Coral Group, London

Nov 2017 – Aug 2018

AWS Cloud Engineer, Cloud Guild (contract)

- Maintenance and contribution to the Cloud Framework used by all projects within LCG being onboarded to AWS
- Automation of on environments for the Ladbrokes Sports Front End, using a combination of Terraform, Chef and Jenkins
- Supporting teams new to Cloud concepts through daily assistance and guidance which would result in members becoming self-sufficient. Beneficial for long term growth of the workforce's capabilities

## Tesco Technology, Welwyn Garden City

Dec 2016 - Nov 2017

**AWS DevOps Engineer** (contract)

- Engineering and overall enhancement of an in-house AWS "Cloud Capability Centre" platform
- Automating compliance checks across 100+ AWS accounts leveraging resources such as Lambda, Config Rules, IAM, SQS/SNS
- Integrating Splunk Monitoring across the vast number of VPC's in Tesco
- Used Technology; Terraform, Chef, Jenkins, Ruby, Python, Node.is, Vagrant and Packer

### Chef, London

**Solutions Architect** (Non-exclusive contract)

Jul 2016 – Dec 2016

- Covering post-sales consultancy for clients such as Principality, ABN Amro and EuroJust
- Delivering 'vmware provisioning' and application deployment cookbooks
- Comprehensive write-ups and recommendations given to clients post on-site consultancy

**Contino,** UK Jan 2015 – July 2016

Senior DevOps Consultant, Automation & DevOps (Rolling Contract @ Capital One)

- Effectively transformed the Automation team's way of working by introducing key DevOps methods and best practices while using Agile SCRUM for delivery
- Introducing concepts such as TDD, Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery and Distributed Version Control (GIT)
- Leveraging AWS resources such as VPC, EC2 and CloudFormation while still maintaining an onpremise VMWare vSphere datacenter
- Designing usage patterns for tools such Jenkins, Chef, Packer, Terraform and Docker
- Scripting in Ruby, Bash and Python

### Accenture, London

### **Lead Technical Architect,** *DevOps Control Services*

May 2013 – Dec 2014

- Strategizing the development architecture and DevOps for a leading European financial services implementing its new post-trade platform.
- Created the Continuous Integration and Deployment Pipeline for the transition of code/config artefacts throughout the testing lifecycle to production in a seamless and automated manner.
- Applied tools such as Jenkins and Chef to assist continuous delivery and configuration management.

**Technical Architect,** Scottish & Southern Energy (Accenture engagement) Jun 2012 – May 2013

- Effectively applied DevOps best practices and processes to manage build and deployments of the config items for Oracle Utilities packaged platform.
- Ensuring the build and deployment process was kept up to date with constantly evolving requirements.
- Built an invaluable working relationship with the build leads, test leads, environment leads and operations team to improve the overall collaboration.
- Applied tools such as Jenkins, ClearCase, ClearQuest and Accenture's in-house build & deployment automation tool.

**Tech Arch Senior Analyst,** DCSC + EDF Energy (Accenture engagement) Jul 2009 - Jun 2012

- Led a team based onshore (London), Manila and Mumbai who were involved in resolving configuration management, build and deployment related support requests.
- Solved an ongoing delivery issue by providing automated delta deployments of the Oracle Fusion middleware.

**Accenture**, London (1 Year Industrial Placement)

Jul 2007- Aug 2008

**Associate Software Engineer**, VISA (Accenture engagement)

- Role involved coordinating optimizing Java source code in compliance for the project standard.
- Following defined processes and using standard development tool sets (IBM Rational Software Architect, IBM ClearCase and DB2).

### **EDUCATION**

**2005 – 2009 City University** 

Bachelors of Science (Hons) Business Computing Systems, Achieved Degree: 2:1

### TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS

May 2017 – Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate, License: M1YSQE1CCBQ1Q2KB

Nov 2014 – **Amazon Web Services** 

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate, License: AWS-ASA-4520

Oct 2013 - ITIL

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management, License: QU30120655

Jan 2008 - Sun Microsystems

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST